「良医」前情回顾
Previously on "The Good Doctor"...
表现得像个普通人能有多难
How hard can it be to just act like a normal human being?!
不
No!
你能别玩你那破兔子了吗
Stop petting that stupid rabbit!
我们再也不会回家了
We're never going home again.
我们有彼此  这就够了
We have each other, and that's all we need.
我的弟弟在我眼前去了天堂
My brother went to heaven in front of my eyes.
永远记住  你是最聪明的
Never forget, you're the smart one.
我为你骄傲  肖恩
And I'm proud of you, Shaun.
爸
Dad?
潘妮  我也好想你
Penny, I missed you, too!
潘妮  过来
Oh, Penny, come.
坐好
Stay.
爸
Hey, Dad.
抱歉这么早过来  我刚下飞机
Sorry it's so early. I just landed.
其实你来得有点晚
Actually, you're a bit late.
晚了五星期
Five weeks.
我知道
I know. I know.
很抱歉  说来话长  好吗
I'm sorry. I-i-it's a long story, okay?
当时的情况如何
But h-how was it?
那可是你母亲的葬礼
It was your mother's funeral.
爸  我...
Dad, I'm...
好了
Okay.
你有我的电话
Well, you have my cell number.
你得接电话才行啊
It only works if you answer it.
爸
Dad?
Dad?!
爸
Dad!
你还好吗
You okay?
还好吗  不能呼吸吗
You okay? You can't breathe?!
不能  好
No? Okay.
坚持住  我报警求救
Hold on, I'm gonna call for help, okay?
911吗  我爸晕倒了
911? My dad collapsed!
他不能呼吸  拜托快点来
He can't -- he can't breathe, please hurry!
坚持住  爸
Just hold on, Dad!
早上好  各位
Good morning, everyone!
真准时
Right on time.
你是睡这了  还是用了任意门
What, did you sleep here or use a teleportation device?
我用了任意门
I used a teleportation device.
无意义的问题通常暗含讽刺
Nonsensical questions usually imply sarcasm,
我发现人们通常也以讽刺回答
which I've found people often answer sarcastically.
真棒
Good one.
创伤科请求会诊  患者为66岁男性
Trauma wants a consult on a 66-year-old male
因严重过敏导致晕倒
who collapsed from severe anaphylaxis,
同时伴有呼吸停止
complicated by respiratory arrest.
他儿子刚从泰国回来
His son just got back from Thailand.
这位父亲就马上过敏发作了
Almost immediately, the father had his allergic reaction.
患者有一些过敏原
Patient has a few allergies --
花粉  霉菌  贝类
pollen, mold, shellfish --
但没发现明显的相关过敏原
but no corresponding allergens were in evidence.
为什么要给过敏患者做外科会诊
Why are we doing a surgical consult on an allergy?
我们没有
Well, we're not.
会诊针对的是他现在的腹部剧痛
We're doing a consult on the excruciating abdominal pain he now has.
你也听到了
As you may have heard.
威尔克斯先生  我是尼尔·梅伦德斯医生
Mr. Wilks, hi, I'm Dr. Neil Melendez.
听说你腹部疼痛
Heard you had some abdominal pain.
原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
翻 译     Z小花儿       长尾电阻
翻 译     bellelulu      琦小果      屯栗子
翻 译     迷失_绽放      八步半
校 对     Santolalla
{an8\b0\pos(183,215)\fad(500,500)\fn方正黑体_GBK\fs42\c&HFFFFFF&\3c&HBDC0BD&\2c&HFFFFFF&\4c&HBBBEBB&}良     医
{an8\b0\pos(237,125)\fad(500,500)\fn方正黑体_GBK\fs22\c&HFFFFFF&\3c&HBDC0BD&\2c&HFFFFFF&\4c&HBBBEBB&}第一季    第五集
时间轴    海默迷妹念    海默迷姐查
后 期     斯人
他疼得很厉害
The guy was in some serious pain --
需要注射十毫克吗啡的程度
10 milligrams of morphine worth.
总 监     夕橙
检查结果显示脂肪酶
Test results show elevated lipase,
淀粉酶和胰蛋白都增高了
amylase, pancreatic enzymes.
胰腺增大
Pancreas is enlarged.
可能是酒精诱发的胰腺炎
Could be pancreatitis, maybe alcohol-induced.
儿子说早上六点就在他父亲身上闻到了酒气
The son said he smelled alcohol on his father 6:00 in the morning.
过敏性反应是胰腺炎诱发的症状
And anaphylaxis has been known to precipitate attacks of pancreatitis.
大概就是这样了
Guess that's it, then.
看来你不认同
Meaning you totally disagree.
不是谁都会一大早就喝巴克泡腾酒
Not everyone who starts their day off with a Mimosa
折腾坏自己的胰腺
fries their pancreas.
你的眼神肯定比我好多了
Your eyesight must a hell of a lot better than mine.
由于肠道气体的覆盖
Because I can't see the entire pancreas
我可没看到完整的胰腺
due to the overlying bowel gas.
预约腹部CT  好好看清楚
We'll order an abdominal CT and take a better look.
这就对了
There you go.
莫菲去哪儿了
Where the hell is Murphy?
骨折很严重  但不需要钢钉
It's a severe fracture, but I don't think you'll need pins.
年轻人的骨头愈合能力很好
Young bones tend to heal very well.
「年轻人的骨头」
Young Bones?
那不是「星际迷航: 原初」的漫画小说吗
Isn't that a "Star Trek: Origins" graphic novel?
我不知道
I'm not sure.
不  我开玩笑的
No, that was a joke.
你的父母在哪儿
Where are your parents?
他们在路上了
They're coming.
他们在市里上班  所以开过来有点远
They both work in the city, so it's a long drive for them.
我本来在参加野外考察
I was on a school field trip,
结果自己绊倒了
and I tripped over my own feet.
竟然正好摔在谢尔比·洛马尔面前
Of course, it was right in front of Shelby Lomar.
至少样子非常狼狈
At least it was pretty gross,
所以我起码得了点同情分
so I got some sympathy points for that.
我还以为你的骨折是由更严重的事故造成的
I would expect this to have been caused by a more serious accident.
不  就是绊倒了
Nope, just a trip.
我经常绊倒
I do that a lot.
我也很无奈
What can I say?
我笨手笨脚的
I'm clumsy.
好  盯着我的手指
Yes. Now follow my finger.
你有点眼球震颤和不自主眼运动
You have some nystagmus -- an involuntary eye movement.
什么意思
So what's that mean?
你摔倒时伤到头了吗
When you fell, did you hit your head?
没有
No.
你觉得我有脑损伤吗
What, you think I have brain damage?
眼球震颤可能是神经系统问题的症状
Nystagmus can be a sign of a neurological issue.
难怪我在社会调研里只得了C
Well, that would explain the "C" I got in social studies.
你又在开玩笑吧
That was another joke, wasn't it?
我去给你预约脑部CT
I'm going to order a head CT for you.
去吧
Go for it.
-肖恩  你睡觉了吗  -睡了
- Shaun, are you getting any sleep? - Yes.
是吗  真的睡觉了吗
Really? I mean, really getting sleep?
我准时到了医院
I got here on time.
那很好
Well, that's good.
我用了任意门
I used a teleportation device.
麻烦给我放射科表单
Radiology form, please.
肖恩  那个男孩看起来很像...
Shaun, that boy, he looks like...
史蒂夫  没错
Steve. He does.
他们有血缘关系吗
Is he related?
他叫埃文·格里克  应该没有
His name is Evan Gallico, so I don't think so.
这太不可思议了
That is uncanny.
只是巧合而已
Just coincidental.
他跟你弟弟简直一模一样
He looks exactly like your brother.
并不是完全一样
No, he doesn't.
他的头发短一些
His hair is shorter.
我被吓到了  你没被吓到吗
It freaks me out. It doesn't freak you out?
没有
No.
吓到了也没关系
It's okay if it does --
不  他不是史蒂夫  史蒂夫已经死了
No, he's not Steve. Steve's dead.
我说「我用了任意门」是玩笑话
"I used a teleportation device" was a joke.
那...很好
Yeah, that's...that's good.
我没能参加妈妈的葬礼是因为我恋爱了
So, I couldn't come to Mom's funeral because I fell in love.
她也是学校里的老师
She was another teacher at the school.
一个泰国女人
A Thai woman.
她很善良
And she was kind and --
美丽  有爱心...
and beautiful and loving...
但病得很重
and very, very sick.
她有先天性心脏缺损
She had a congenital heart defect.
如果你不愿意告诉我
Look, if you don't want to tell me
这六个月你去哪里了  那就别说
where you've been for the last six months, then don't.
这是你的事
It's your business.
但是别侮辱我的智商
But don't insult my intelligence.
我不能丢下她
Well, I couldn't just leave her.
你连花五分钟打个电话的时间都没有吗
You couldn't leave her for five minutes to make a phone call?
打扰到你们了吗
This a bad time?
没有  请进
No, come in.
CT结果显示  你的胰腺有病变
According to the CT, you have a lesion on your pancreas.
可能是什么病变
Well, what do you think this lesion could be?
还不确定
Not sure.
所以我们需要做病理切片检查
That's why we need to biopsy it.
可能只是个良性囊肿
It could just be a benign cyst.
或者
Or...?
Or...
可能是癌症  对吗
it could be cancer, right?
我们很快就能知道了
We'll know soon enough.
这很快的
This won't take long.
我知道  我已经做过两次了
I know. I've had two of these.
再来一次我就能有童军勋章了
One more and I get my Scout badge.
这很好笑
That was funny.
没看到你的表情  很难说
Tough to tell without looking at you,
但我猜你在讽刺我
but I'm guessing that was sarcasm.
不是  我有自闭症
No. I have autism,
因此我很难读懂社交暗示
which makes it hard for me to read social cues.
我也无法理解笑话
Jokes are difficult.
我以前认识一个有自闭症的小孩  皮特
I used to know a kid with autism. Peter.
他有点奇怪  但是人非常好
He was kind of weird but super nice.
以前认识
Used to know?
你现在不认识他了吗
You don't know him anymore?
他去世了
He died.
出了车祸
Hit by a car.
你有朋友去世吗
You know anyone who died?
我的弟弟
My brother.
真糟糕
That sucks.
你为什么做那么多CT扫描
Why did you have the other CT scans?
我的父母有...
My parents have...
你们把害怕生病称作什么
uh, what's the word for fear of getting sick?
疑病症
Hypochondriasis?
不是  比这个更严重
no, worse than that.
他们有患病恐怖症
They have...nosophobia.
我喜欢那个词
I love that word.
你觉得甘尼特小姐怎么样
What do you think of Miss Gannett?
她很好
She's nice.
她臀很翘
I think she's callipygian.
她什么
She's what?
臀很翘
Callipygian?
意思是「臀部线条很美」  肖恩
It means "having shapely buttocks," Shaun.
你读了字典
You read the dictionary.
情节上缺什么  就在词汇上补回来
What it lacks in plot, it makes up for in vocab.
你结婚了吗
So, you married?
女朋友呢
Girlfriend?
男朋友
Boyfriend?
热带鱼
Tropical fish?
我喜欢莉亚
I like Lea.
莉亚是谁
And who's Lea?
莉亚是一个朋友
Lea is a friend.
可以约会的朋友
A friend you date?
可以打炮的朋友
A friend with benefits?
我偶尔借给她电池
I lend her batteries sometimes.
我喜欢这个进展
I like where this is going...
那就继续加油吧
So, you know, keep going.
如果你不加油  我会的
'Cause if you don't, I will.
我就是这样
It's kind of my thing, you know?
说起话来没完  骚扰所有人
Just constant talking -- annoys everyone.
-莫菲  -也不是所有人
- Murphy. - Well, I guess not everyone.
我的家人现在已经习惯了
My family's pretty used to me now. I mean...
我的朋友们也都是话痨  所以...
my friends are very talkative as well, so...
你给一个手臂骨折的人做脑CT
You're giving the fractured arm a head CT?
-是的  -去照顾那个胰腺患者吧
- Yes. - Get back to the pancreas.
他不是笨手笨脚
He's not clumsy.
他内耳附近有脑肿瘤
He has a brain tumor behind the inner ear.
别管胰腺患者了
Forget the pancreas.
格里克夫妇
Mr. And Mrs. Gallico?
我是肖恩·莫菲医生
I'm Dr. Shaun Murphy.
我负责治疗您的儿子
I'm treating your son.
他怎么样了
Well, how is he?
我们听说摔得很严重
We were told it was a bad break,
但应该能完全康复
but it should heal no problem.
我知道埃文为什么摔倒了
I know why Evan tripped.
他左耳后侧的颞骨处有肿瘤
He had a tumor in the temporal bone behind his left ear,
影响了他的平衡功能
which is affecting his balance.
我安排了与肿瘤科纳吉德医生的会诊
I've arranged for a consult with Dr. Najid in oncology
-她会... -不用了  我们...
- and she's going... - No, that won't be necessary. We...
我们已经有肿瘤科医师了
We already have an oncologist.
埃文被确诊为晚期骨肉瘤
Evan's been diagnosed with stage four osteosarcoma.
他抱怨过胫骨痛
He was complaining of a sore shin.
我们最没想到的就是骨癌
The last thing that we expected was bone cancer.
旧金山市立医院的医生说他只能活一年
The doctors at SFM, they gave him a year to live.
七个月前说的
That was seven months ago.
骨肉瘤解释了他的骨折为什么这么严重
Osteosarcoma explains the severity of his fracture --
看来他还是需要钢钉固定
he will need pins in his arm after all.
我们可以去看看他吗
can we see him?
当然  他在414房间
Yes. He's in room 414.
莫菲医生
Dr. Murphy?
他不知道自己患了癌症
He doesn't know about his diagnosis.
我们想继续向他保密
We would really like to keep it that way.
他才是患者
He's the patient.
他没有权利知道真相吗
Doesn't he have the right to know the truth?
没有  他还未成年  所以没有权利
Well, no. He's also a minor, so, no, he doesn't.
埃文很聪明
Evan's very intelligent --
他承受得住
he'd be able to handle it.
肖恩  或许这不只关系到埃文
Well, Shaun, maybe it's not just about Evan.
或许也关系到他的父母
Maybe it's about his parents, as well.
或许他们现在无法向埃文开口
Maybe it's just too difficult for them to tell Evan right now.
我不清楚
I don't know.
那他父母才不应该知道真相
Then they're the ones who shouldn't be told.
我这么问你吧  肖恩
Well, let me ask you this, Shaun --
让埃文尽可能地享受
what's so wrong about Evan being allowed
他现在的生活有什么错
to enjoy as much of his life as possible?
埃文想知道真相
Evan wants to know the truth.
你怎么知道
How do you know that?
如果他是史蒂夫  是你弟弟
If this were Steve, if this were your brother,
他会想知道真相吗
would he want to know the truth?
是这样吗
Is that what this is?
爸爸总是这样
Dad's such a tool.
我在他的壁橱里发现了我的生日礼物
I found my birthday present in their closet,
他总把东西藏在那
right where they always hide it.
我正要拆开就被爸爸发现了  吓死我了
I was just about to open it when Dad caught me snooping and freaked out.
我讨厌那些虚假的惊喜
I hate all that phony surprise stuff.
那是个水雷水枪
It's an AquaBlast Water Cannon.
妈妈买的时候我也在
I was with Mom when she bought it.
多谢你  肖恩
Thank you, Shaun.
你的坦诚真是别具一格
Your honesty's refreshing!
没错  他想知道真相
Yes, he would want to know the truth.
我们对此都无能为力
Well, there's nothing we can do about it.
这不是你能做的决定  是他们的
It's not your decision -- it's theirs.
那是他们的儿子
He's their son.
克莱尔  我需要你帮忙
Claire, I need you.
当然  怎么了
Sure, what's up?
我需要有人替我撒谎
I need someone to lie for me.
好吧
Okay...
我真是受宠若惊
I'm flattered?
医生
Hey, doc?
我有件事要告诉我爸
There's something I need to tell my dad.
我们没给他换房间  他还在326房间
We haven't moved him. He's still in room, uh, 326.
你有什么医学问题要问我吗
Do you have a medical question for me?
他快死了吗
Is he dying?
我们还不清楚
We don't know yet.
活检结果出来以后我们会更清楚
The biopsy will tell us more.
好吧
Okay.
我爸爸人很好
My dad is a good guy.
但我们从来都聊不来
We've just never been on the same page, you know?
我和我妈聊得更多
My mother was the one that I could talk to --
他也是
same for him.
所以  她不在
So, without her,
我们俩就像废人一样
we're both pretty useless.
326房间
Room 326.
好的
Right.
莫菲医生叫我过来跟你们说说不同的意见
Dr. Murphy called me in for a second opinion.
你的胳膊需要钢钉固定
you need some pins in your arm.
为什么  有什么变化吗
Why? What's changed?
我们看了你的放射报告
Well, after studying the radiology report,
考虑到你骨折的严重程度
given how bad the break is,
我们认为对骨折进行彻底有效的修复
we just think it would be a prudent step
才是比较慎重周全的治疗方法
to ensure an efficient and thorough mending to the break.
我还能再打棒球吗
Will I be able to play baseball again?
我觉得完全可以
Well, I don't see why not,
只要经过理疗  等骨折痊愈就可以
once it's completely healed, after some physiotherapy.
等多长时间我才能投球
How long before I can pitch?
这不好说
It's hard to say.
他想找个人替他撒谎
He wanted someone to lie for him.
他选了你
And he picked you.
梅里尔的儿子想征求些个人建议
Merrill's son asked for personal advice.
他选了你
And he picked you.
就是说啊
I know, right?
他有事瞒着他爸
He's lying to his dad about something.
是吗  什么事
Yeah? What?
我不知道
I don't know.
你没问吗
You didn't ask?
和病情无关
It didn't seem relevant, medically.
做个人类也没那么难
You know it's not that difficult to be a human being.
就跟他说「讲明真相」
Just tell him to "come clean,"
「诚为上策」
"Honesty is the best policy,"
「谎言是压在你心上的重担」
"A lie is a stone in your heart."
最后一句是谁说的
Who said the last one?
我说的
Me.
是我编的
I made it up.
我找到了
And...I got it.
他过敏了
He's anaphylactic.
-给我肾上腺素  -我正在退出来
- Would you get me an epi? - I'm coming out.
喉痉挛了  把管拔出来
The throat's constricting. Pull the tube.
「布朗医生」怎么样了
So, what's up with "Dr. Browne"?
她就是莉亚  对吗
She's Lea, isn't she?
克莱尔是我的同事
Claire is my colleague.
得了吧  我注意到你看她的眼神了
Oh, come on, I saw the way you were looking at her.
什么眼神
How?
我可没这样
I don't think I look like that.
好吧  那你为什么叫她来「会诊」
Okay, so then why'd you call her in for a "consult"?
好吧
Okay.
她比我更擅长与人交流
Yes, she's better at talking to people than I am.
这句话里我听出来了50个谎言
I counted like 50 tells there.
-你真的不擅长说谎  -我知道
- You really suck at lying. - I know.
太糟了  这可是重要的社交技巧
Too bad. It's an important social skill.
你怎么知道什么时候该撒谎
So how do you know when to lie?
如果人们需要知道什么
When people need to know things,
他们就需要知道
they need to know.
如果他们不需要
If they don't,
那就别有心理负担地撒个谎
lie through your teeth and feel good about it.
如果他们需要知道真相
What if they need to know the truth,
但真相会伤到他们呢
but it'll hurt them?
有些人可以承受  有些人不行
Some can handle it, some can't.
你怎么知道谁行谁不行
So how do you know who can and who can't?
那你就说实话
You tell the truth.
如果说了后他们还喜欢你  你就知道了
If they like you after, then you'll know.
如果他们不喜欢我了呢
If they don't?
那就也无所谓了
Then it doesn't really matter anyway.
你得了癌症
You have cancer.
我知道
Yeah, I know.
之前我腿痛  我父母带我去了医院
My parents took me in for a sore leg.
做了很多检查
After a whole bunch of tests,
医生找了他们谈话
they talked to the doctor,
他们出来后告诉我没事
then came out and told me I was fine.
就这样  「没事」
That's it. Just "fine."
隔天他们就给我买了PS4游戏机
The next day, they bought me a PS4.
所以我去谷歌上搜索了我的症状
So I Googled my symptoms,
把范围缩小到骨肉瘤或者发育痛
and I narrowed it down to osteosarcoma or growing pains.
但父母不可能因为发育痛就给你买游戏机
Kids don't get gaming systems for growing pains.
没关系的
It's okay.
我不怕死
I'm not afraid to die.
你不怕吗
You're not?
如果死的过程痛苦  那确实挺糟  但...
Well, I mean, the dying part will suck if it hurts, but...
我是不怕死亡本身的
I'm not afraid about the actual death part.
因为你相信自己死后会上天堂吗
Because you believe you're going to Heaven?
因为我不相信
Because I don't.
如果我相信有天堂
If I believe in Heaven,
我就得相信上帝的存在
then I got to believe in God,
我就得相信是上帝让我生病的
then I got to believe God made me sick.
那也太复杂了
How messed up is that?
相信这一切都是随机发生的就简单多了
It's just easier to think that it's all random.
当死亡来临的时候  一切就...
And when it's over, it's just...
结束了
over.
莉亚是怎么回事
So what about Lea?
你们在哪认识的
Where'd you guys meet?
在过道里
In the hallway.
真是个美丽的故事
That's a beautiful story.
是的  她是我的邻居
Yes. She's my neighbor.
真方便
Convenient.
他又有过敏反应了
He had another allergic reaction.
-那位胰腺患者  -对  梅里尔·威尔克斯
- The pancreas? - Merrill Wilks, yeah.
这次发作比第一次还要严重
And the second attack was even more severe than the first.
发生在我们做胰腺病变组织活体切片检查的时候
It coincided with biopsying the pancreatic lesion,
现在看  似乎是个囊肿
which now appears was a cyst.
我们现在知道他是对囊肿里面的物质过敏
Well, now we know he's allergic to whatever's in that cyst.
我们还知道再有一次囊肿破裂他可能会死
We also know that the next cyst that pops will probably kill him.
如果他还能等到下一次
Well, if there is a next.
去做几项检查
Let's run a couple tests,
看他体内是否有寄生虫
see if there's any evidence of parasites.
给他做全身核磁共振检查
And MRI his entire body --
如果我们够幸运
if we're lucky,
他只有这两个囊肿的话  就能出院了
he only had the two cysts and he can go home.
你在找漏洞吗
Are you looking for loopholes?
想要救埃文
Hoping to save Evan?
所有人都会犯错
Everyone makes mistakes.
那你得把医院所有的文件都再检查一遍
Which means you should double-check every file in the hospital.
他的嗜中性粒细胞计数为634
The oncologist flagged his
被肿瘤科医师标为偏低
neutrophil count of 634 as low.
那确实挺低的
That is low.
是正常范围内的低
Low normal.
这句话里不还是有个「低」字吗
I can still hear the word "Low" In there.
他只是个孩子
He's just a kid.
我理解想到他死掉有多难受
I know how hard it is to think of him dying.
他自己能接受
He's okay with that.
真令人难以置信
I find that hard to believe.
我们都会死
We all die --
如果大家能接受这一点  会更开心
if we accepted that, we'd be happier.
也许吧  但是人都是不知足的
Maybe. But we're not good with contentment.
与死亡斗争是我们生存的意义
Fighting death is what keeps us alive.
我发现了  是棘球绦虫
We got a hit -- Echinococcus.
「棘球绦虫」
Echinococcus?
囊肿里全都是绦虫吗
The cysts are filled with tapeworms?
还有其他囊肿吗
Cysts? There are more?
还有三个
Three more?
还有四个  他大脑里还有
Four more. You missed the one in his brain.
-格拉斯曼医生  -什么事
- Dr. Glassman? - Yeah?
你曾是一名神经外科医生  对吧
You used to be a neurosurgeon, right?
没错
So they say.
帮我拿一下
Take this, will you?
我需要一位  你有人可以推荐吗
I need one. Who would you recommend?
什么情况
What you got?
真厉害
That's cool.
我的脑子里怎么会有绦虫
How the hell did I get tapeworms in my head?
不知道  但确实有
No idea, but you do.
你可能是通过土狼或者狼接触到的虫卵
You can pick up the eggs from coyotes or wolves.
你接触过狼或者土狼吗
You been hanging around coyotes or wolves?
我住在郊区
I live in the suburbs --
连儿童动物园都没有
we don't even have a petting zoo.
你的囊肿已经存在一段时间了
You might've had these cysts for quite some time.
其中一个破裂
When one of them burst,
导致了你的第一次过敏反应
that's what caused the first allergic reaction.
为什么会破裂
Well, why did it burst?
Why did it burst?
任何突然的动作  扭曲  转动或压迫
Any sudden movements, twists, turns, squeeze.
拥抱呢
A hug?
有可能
Could be.
但第二次发作时你不在场
But you weren't there for the second one.
我做活体组织切片检查时刺破了你的囊肿
I punctured the cyst on your pancreas during the biopsy.
你也看到了  过敏反应会逐次严重
As you've seen, allergic reactions get worse each time they happen.
要是再发生  就糟了
So a third one, that would be bad.
那会...
That would be...
会非常糟糕
That would be very bad.
因此我们计划通过手术来完整除去所有囊肿
So we're gonna have to surgically remove all the cysts intact.
格拉斯曼医生是全国声誉最高的
Dr. Glassman's one of the most highly acclaimed
神经外科医生之一
neurosurgeons in the state.
他做手术你可以放心了
You are very lucky to have him.
卡卢医生拍马屁也越来越厉害了
And Dr. Kalu is fast becoming a very accomplished flatterer.
颅内的囊肿很重要
The cranial cyst, that is a big deal.
我们得打开颅骨顶部
We're gonna have to take off the top of your skull.
你们要进到我脑袋里面去
You'd be digging in to my brain?
差不多是这样
Well, yeah, pretty much.
用生理盐水
With saline.
轻轻地用它移置囊肿
We use it to gently displace the cyst,
然后  它就奇迹般地出来了
and then, poof, it magically pops out.
有点像生孩子的过程
Kind of like delivering a baby.
如果分娩没有痛感的话
You know, if childbirth were painless.
之后再继续处理其他囊肿
And then we move on to the other cysts.
我们会治好你的
Hey, we're gonna take good care of you.
37度  轻度皮疹
轻度皮疹
埃文没得癌症
Evan doesn't have cancer.
BGM: Run The Jewels by Run The Jewels
可能不是癌症
It might not be cancer!
看看你连续两次准时到了
Look at you on time -- two for two.
可能不是癌症
It might not be cancer.
-胳膊骨折患者  -是的
- Fractured arm? - Yes.
你说他被确诊为患有晚期骨肉瘤
You said he'd been diagnosed with stage four osteosarcoma.
埃文八个月前被确诊的
Evan was diagnosed with the flu eight months ago,
但他更符合感染埃-巴二氏病毒的症状
but his symptoms were actually a better fit with Epstein-Barr virus,
与朗格汉斯细胞组织细胞增生症有关
which is linked to Langerhans cell histiocytosis,
这会导致上肢长骨部位产生溶骨性病变
which causes osteolytic lesions in the long bones of the upper limbs.
而病变可能被误诊为骨肉瘤的症状
And those lesions could be misdiagnosed as signs of osteosarcoma.
-的确  -那他的脑肿瘤呢
- Yes. - What about his brain tumor?
朗格汉斯细胞也会在颅骨中出现
Langerhans can also manifest in the skull.
也就是说不是死亡诊断
Instead of a death sentence,
他的病可以用泼尼松轻松治愈是吗
he could have something that could easily be treated with prednisone?
接下来需要做骨髓穿刺进行确认
Next, we need to do a bone-marrow aspiration to confirm.
你应该看过他的病历了
I assume you've looked at his file.
看了很久
For a very long time.
上面肯定有活体组织检查
Well, there must've been a biopsy.
病理报告上怎么说
What did the pathology report say?
没错  做过两次活体组织检查
Yes. There were two biopsies.
两次都显示有骨肉瘤
Both were positive for osteosarcoma.
-莫菲  -他们可能误诊了
- Murphy... - They could be false positives.
你知道两次都误诊的可能性有多低吗
Do you have any idea how unlikely it is to have two false positives?
百分之零点三
0.3%.
因此我们倾向于认为这「不可能」
Which we can comfortably round off to "not likely."
但也有可能...
It is possible --
没错  但这意味着让濒死孩童的父母
Yes, but it means telling the parents of a dying child
去盼望一件根本没有可能的事
that there's hope, when really there isn't.
洗个澡准备巡房吧
Grab a shower and get ready for rounds.
-想象力与创造力  -没错
- Imaginative and creative. - Yes.
你正确的几率有多少
What are the chances you're right?
百分之零点三
0.3%.
330之1
330 to 1.
是333之1
333 to 1.
你真的认为值得让埃文父母经受这一切吗
You really think that it's worth putting Evan's parents through all this?
当然
Of course.
如果我们做了333次诊断
If we did this 333 times,
就意味着我们用大约四小时
we'd be giving false hope to 332 people
给了332个人虚假的希望
for approximately four hours,
但我们能拯救一个生命
and we'd save one life.
难道不值得吗
Isn't that worth it?
但梅伦德斯医生不允许我申请检测许可
Anyway, Dr. Melendez won't let me ask for consent to test.
如果我不告诉他们我在做什么呢
What if I don't tell them what I'm doing?
公然违反医德  这就是你的办法吗
A blatant ethics violation -- that's your solution?
没错
Yes.
我该怎么做
How do I do that?
就直接检测别告诉别人  谁也别说
You do it and then don't tell anyone. No one.
如果有人问起
If anyone asks...
就说主治医生注意到红血球数低  要找原因
your attending noticed a low RBC count and needed to find the cause...
就这样  没什么大不了的
that's it -- no biggie.
你知道圣克拉17街的威尔克斯杂货铺吗
You know Wilks' Grocery on Santa Clara 17th?
它已经建立近60年了
It's been an institution for nearly 60 years.
我祖父母于1958年开了这家店
My grandparents started it in 1958,
我和妻子在1982年接手
and my wife and I took it over in '82.
我妻子生病后
But when my wife got sick
我开始跟凯文说接手的事
and I started talking to Kevin about taking it over,
而他就那么离开了
he just... took off.
对他来说  那就是个卖生菜和厕纸的地方
To him, it was just a place to sell lettuce and toilet paper.
我父亲在英国开了一家房地产开发公司
My father chairs a real-estate development company in the U.K.
认为我是设立美国分公司的最佳人选
Thought I'd be the perfect person to set up the U.S. office.
但你想加入「救人行业」  是吗
You wanted to be in the "helping profession" ?
我想做我的专业
I wanted to be in my profession.
不在于企业的大小
It's not about how small or how big the venture is,
而在于做属于自己的事
it's about doing something that's yours.
我猜是吧
I guess.
他小时候  我们很亲密
When he was little, we were inseparable.
他很爱来店里「工作」
he used to love to come to the store to "work."
我给他做了个小围裙
I even had a little apron made for him --
上面还绣着他的名字
had his name on it, too.
不过你知道  孩子嘛
Still, you know, kids...
总会长大
grow up.
他还跟母亲很亲密我就很感激了
I'm just grateful that he stayed close to his mother.
他跟她无话不谈
He could talk to her, tell her anything.
我也是
So could I.
但她去世以后
And when she went...
我失去了他们两个
I lost them both.
他现在回来了
Looks like he's back now.
我只知道在我需要他的时候他丢下了我
All I know is he ditched me when I needed him.
正如智者所说
Well, you know, as a wise person once said,
「心怀怨恨是压在心里的重担」
"Holding a grudge is a stone in your heart."
这是做什么的
What's that for?
骨髓穿刺的局部麻醉
Local anaesthetic for a bone-marrow aspiration.
为什么要做骨髓穿刺
Why do I need a bone-marrow aspiration?
主治医生注意到你红血球数低
My attending saw a low RBC count
需要找到原因
and wants to find the cause --
没什么大不了的
no biggie.
「没什么大不了的」
"No biggie"?
你说谎
You're lying.
怎么回事
What's going on?
你已经告诉我是癌症晚期
You already told me I have terminal cancer,
还能更糟吗
what's worse than that?
你可能没得癌症
You might not.
可能不是骨肉瘤
It might not be osteosarcoma --
可能是朗格汉斯细胞组织细胞增生症
might be Langerhans cell histiocytosis,
是可治愈的
which is treatable.
可治愈
Treatable?
就是说  我可能不会死
As in, I might not die?
所以我需要做穿刺来验证
That's why I need to aspirate to find out for sure.
我父母知道吗
Do my parents know?
他们告诉我不要点燃你父母的希望
I was told not to get their hopes up.
那我们趁他们没回来  快做吧
Then let's do it before they get back.
请侧过身去
Roll onto your side.
有没有做穿刺的童军徽章啊
Is there a Scout badge for aspirations?
我觉得刚刚有人说了个笑话
I think someone just made a joke.
你们好
Hello.
你们在做什么
What are you doing?
止疼药
Painkiller.
我胳膊疼
My arm hurts.
这并不能解释我为什么要在你的腰部注射
That wouldn't explain why I'd be injecting your lumbar region.
好吧  你们好
Okay. Yes, hello.
我觉得埃文的癌症可能是误诊
I think Evan may have been misdiagnosed with cancer.
我认为他患有其他会造成骨骼
I think he has something that creates bone lesions
看起来像骨肉瘤的病变
that look like osteosarcoma.
可能性很小  只有0.3%  但是我...
It's a small chance, 0.3%, but I --
你告诉埃文他得了癌症
You -- You told Evan that he has cancer?
现在你又告诉他  告诉我们他没得
And now you are telling him -- and us that he doesn't?
我是告诉你们他也许没有
I'm telling you he might not.
所以我需要做个穿刺
That's why I need to perform this aspiration.
他说我可能还有救
He says whatever I have might be treatable.
你疯了吗
Are you insane?
不  我没疯
No. I am not insane.
我以为你们会高兴的
I thought you'd be happy.
两者有显著联系
There is a significant link between
朗格汉斯细胞组织细胞增生症和...
Langerhans cell histiocytosis and --
出去
Go! Get out!
我给你倒点儿水
Let me get you some water.
-天啊  -手在这儿
- Oh, my God! - Hands right here --
接着呢
Right here!
呼吸机  立刻
Respiratory, stat!
他体内有栓塞
He has a massive embolus,
可能是从骨折处出来的
probably thrown from his fracture.
位于肺动脉分叉处
It's located at the bifurcation of the pulmonary arteries.
他快要血流动力塌陷了
He's close to hemodynamic collapse.
这可不是闹着玩的
Yeah, no kidding.
我可以协助
I'd like to assist.
不可能
Not a chance.
好吧  我想协助
Okay. I'd like to assist.
很明显  你对这个病例过于上心了
You're obviously too close to the case.
我认为我这样正好
I think I'm just the right amount of close.
莫菲  你向他父母说谎
Murphy, you lied to the parents
以便能试着证明你的荒谬理论
just so you could try to prove your ridiculous theory.
你太过于上心了
You're too damn close.
骑跨性栓塞  刷手准备手术
Saddle embolism, scrub in.
我们得在他心脏骤停之前去除栓塞
We have to get rid of the embolus before he arrests.
他的心脏几乎不泵血了
His heart is barely pumping blood.
我可以感觉到肺动脉
I can feel the pulmonary artery...
我只需要找到栓塞  在这里
I just need to find the obstruction...there!
找到了
I got it.
手术刀
Knife.
-手术刀  -心电图显示右心损伤
- Knife. - EKG is showing right heart strain.
他坚持不了这么久了
He can't take this much longer.
我知道  但是如果我再快一点儿
I know, but if I move any quicker,
可能会伤到左主动脉  他就死了
I could nick the left main artery and kill the boy.
那句「没什么大不了的」让我暴露了
The phrase "No biggie" gave me away.
你真得学学怎么撒谎  肖恩
You really got to learn how to lie, Shaun.
我有麻烦了吗
Am I in trouble?
是的
Yes.
除非你是对的
Unless you're right.
如果我错了  他们不应该难过
If I'm wrong, they shouldn't be upset.
他们知道  这几乎不可能
They know it's highly unlikely.
虚假的希望  肖恩  这就是残酷
False hope, Shaun... it's just plain cruel.
他跟你聊过了
He talk to you?
你跟他聊了吗
Did you talk to him?
我不知道和他说什么
I don't know what to tell him.
你爱你父亲  不是吗
You love your father, don't you?
当然
Yeah, of course.
他要做脑部手术了
Right. Well, he's about to go in for brain surgery.
风险很大
There's huge risks involved.
不管这个谎言是什么
Whatever this lie is,
你打算余生都背负这个谎言吗
can you live the rest of your life knowing you kept it from him?
我女朋友没病
My -- My girlfriend wasn't sick.
她甩了我
Okay? She dumped me.
她结婚了  还有两个孩子
She's married with two kids --
不打算离开他们
had no intention of leaving them.
我是个傻子
I-I was an idiot.
你心都碎了  这是问题所在吗
You got your heart broken, that's the problem here?
不  不是  爸
No -- no, Dad.
问题在于
The problem is...
我跑去泰国
I didn't run away to Thailand
不是因为我瞧不上威尔克斯杂货铺
because I thought Wilks' Grocery was beneath me.
而是我害怕我永远没法接替你
I was afraid that I would never be able to fill your shoes...
事实证明确实如此
And then I proved myself right.
左肺动脉打开
Left pulmonary artery's open.
弹簧钳
Ring Forceps.
拜托
Come on.
取出来了
Got it.
心电趋于正常
EKG is normalizing.
他没事了
He's okay.
干得好
Nice job.
好的  冲洗左肺动脉  进行缝合
All right, flush the left pulmonary artery and close him up.
好的
Okay.
梅伦德斯医生
Dr. Melendez...
你来看一下
Take a look at this.
候诊室
早日康复
周年快乐
生日
致  约翰和布兰达
和史蒂夫
珍惜你们共度的时光
眷恋拥抱彼此的温暖
结婚周年快乐
来自  德克和安吉
和肖恩
回收利用  肖恩  真负责
Recycling -- Shaun, very responsible.
是本书
It's a book.
很感谢
I appreciate that.
《杀死一只知更鸟》
谢谢  肖恩
Thanks, Shaun.
我们移除了栓塞
We got the embolism.
他还在恢复  情况不错
He's in recovery and he's doing fine.
但我们在里面时有所发现
But while we were in there, we did find something else.
他肋骨有损伤
Lesions on his ribs.
骨肉瘤的确凿证据
Irrefutable proof of osteosarcoma.
转移到胸腔了
It's metastasized to his chest cavity.
我很遗憾
I'm sorry.
抱歉
I'm very sorry.
圣何塞圣文德医院
给它洗个暖乎乎的盐水澡
Give that a nice, warm saline bath.
请给我钳子和泰勒剪
Forceps and Taylor scissors, please.
钳子和泰勒剪
Forceps and Taylor scissors.
谢谢
Thank you.
看那个
Look at that.
就是它建造了埃及金字塔
That's what built the pyramids,
画出蒙娜·丽莎
painted the Mona Lisa,
发明网络
invented the Internet.
那是我们的闯入者
There is our interloper.
请给我挤压球  黛德丽
Squeezeball please, Deidre.
挤压球
Squeezeball?
他取的  不是我们
His name for it, not ours.
盐水轻轻地将囊肿
The saline gently displaces the cyst
从它的躲藏处冲出来
and coaxes it out of its little hiding place --
希望完整无损  我们就不用紧张了
Hopefully in one piece so we don't have to call 911.
加油  现在...
Come on, now...
请给我托盘
Tray, please.
出来了...
There we go...
还差一点点
A little bit more...
现在出来了
And there we go.
搞定
Got it.
他的眼睛很像他父亲
He has his father's eyes.
难以置信
That was incredible.
搞定一个  还有三个
One down, three to go...
他醒了
There he is.
亲爱的
Hi, Sweetie.
怎么了
What's the matter?
没什么
Nothing.
我们只是很高兴  你做得很好
We're just happy you did so great.
你患有栓塞
You had what's called an embolism.
导致肺部动脉被堵
It clogged an artery in your lungs.
好消息是他们已经取出来了
But the good news is they got it.
你会没事的
And you're gonna be just fine.
但...
Still...
患了癌症还是很糟糕吧
too bad about the cancer, huh?
不  不  不
No, no, no, no.
那医生不知道自己在说什么
The doctor did not know what he was talking about --
爸爸  我全知道
Dad, I know all about it.
已经知道很久了
I have for a long time.
我...
I --
我非常遗憾
I am so sorry.
没事的
It's okay.
因为我不会孤单
Because I'm not gonna be alone.
奶奶也会在那里
Grandma's gonna be there, too.
艾琳阿姨
Auntie Arlene.
吉姆叔叔  如果他学会好好说话了
Uncle Jim, if he figured out how to stop swearing.
我给你倒杯水  伙计
I'll get you some water, buddy.
我在附近遛了遛潘妮
So, I took Penny for a walk -- just around the block.
给了它点生皮零食
And I picked her up some of those rawhide treats,
你知道
you know...
以前妈妈常给它的那些
the ones that Mom used to like to give to her.
我想她了  爸
I miss her, Dad.
解除警报了
Coast is clear?
是
Yes.
谢谢
Thank you.
我错了
I was wrong.
你尽力了
You tried.
我错了
I was wrong.
你的父母恨我
Your parents hate me.
我知道
I know.
-我给了你虚假希望  -是
- I gave you false hope. - Yeah.
但在那一刻  还是挺棒的
But for a minute there, it was pretty awesome.
我想请你帮个忙
I'm going to ask you for a favor.
我不会让出许愿基金会名额的
Well, I'm not giving away my Make-A-Wish.
你介意我读点什么给你吗
Would you mind if I read you something?
不会很久
It's not long.
我不介意
That I can do.
《杀死一只知更鸟》
阿提库斯是对的
Atticus was right.
有一次他说你无法理解别人
One time he said you never really know a man
除非你穿上他的鞋走一圈
until you stand in his shoes and walk around in them.
站在拉德利门廊就够了
Just standing on the Radley porch was enough.
街灯很模糊
The streetlights were fuzzy
因为外头正下着细雨
from the fine rain that was falling
我回家的路上
As I made my way home,
我感到苍老...
I felt very old...
BGM: Forest by Rogue Wave
? I can't protect you from the course of life ?
? But you know me and you know I was born to try ?
? It's just the symptom of a middle-aged attack ?
阿提克斯真的很好
Atticus, he was real nice.
他的双手在我下巴之下
His hands were under my chin,
帮我盖被
pulling up the cover,
陪我入睡
tucking it around me.
很多人都是  斯科特  你终会看见真面目
Most people are, Scout, when you finally see them.
他关掉灯  走去杰姆的房间
He turned out the light and went into Jem's room.
他会在那待一整晚
He would be there all night,
等杰姆早上醒来时他也会在那里
and he would be there when Jem waked up in the morning.
听起来是本不错的书
Sounds like a good book.
可以提前给个剧透啊
Could've used a spoiler alert, though.
谢谢
Thank you.
? Confusing you, from what you need ?
? Every hand that you hold ?
? It comes back ?
我读完了
That's all.
? Every word, every ride ?
? It comes back every time ?
? Every time ?